Hannah McCullough

mccullough.hannah@outlook.com | (602) 903-0852 | GitHub

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Innovative full-stack software engineer with skills in building applications & APIs with a user-experience approach. Having a curious mind and a background in customer service, management, and athletics, I bring strong skills in client relations, collaboration, and leadership.

SKILLS

JavaScript, React, RESTful APIs, Node, TypeScript, Python, Content Management Systems, MongoDB, Ruby on Rails, Postman, Git, HTML, CSS, DataDog, Microservices, Bootstrap, Docker, AWS, SQLite, Jira

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Freelance Phoenix, AZ
Web Developer 01/2018 – Present

- Currently developing a full-stack application with extensive user capabilities and public property data utilizing React, JavaScript, TypeScript, Rails, & Active Record
- Modeled custom database schema and REST API with Ruby on Rails, Active Record, & PostgresSQL
- Utilized Auth & bcrypt to authenticate user login and authorize user functionality based on user type
- Designed websites for small businesses using content management systems with enhanced UI/UX, resulting in increased traffic and leads

Synapse Financial Technologies

Software Engineer II

San Francisco, CA (remote) 07/2022 – 10/2023

- Served as team lead providing technical guidance, mentorship, and knowledge to teammates
- Implemented client direct request, quick turnaround feature enhancements in Python RESTful APIs
- Used strong troubleshooting and bug resolution abilities to quickly rectify production API issues using DataDog, EKS, and Postman
- Managed internal & external developer documentation in Confluence that provided a deeper understanding of the technical side of the products & implementations
- Provided consistent results via strong program design & management skills utilizing Jira & LucidChart
- Improved cross-team processes by providing feedback and alternative solutions to leadership, which positively impacted client experience integration changes

USAA Phoenix, AZ Insurance Professional I 09/2018 – 11/2021

- Served as a department facilitator in the Pulse initiative by communicating employee feedback & innovation to executives
- Regularly facilitated team meetings, resulting in an overall increase in team metrics

EDUCATION

Saint Francis University/
Lake Erie college
08/2010 - 05/2014
Bachelor of Arts in Psychology

Athlete

Scottsdale Community College 08/2018 - 12/2022

Associates in Applied Science -

- Web Development
- Web Design

Flatiron School

11/2021 - 03/2022

Certificate

Full-Stack Software Engineering